<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:ns1="https://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://127.0.0.1:5000/zone/Zona%2010%20-%20Sectia%20Rosarium/plant/Pinus%20sylvestris">
    <ns1:label>Pinus sylvestris</ns1:label>
    <ns1:abstract xml:lang="en">Pinus sylvestris, the Scots pine (UK), Scotch pine (US) or Baltic pine, is a species of tree in the pine family Pinaceae that is native to Eurasia. It can readily be identified by its combination of fairly short, blue-green leaves and orange-red bark.</ns1:abstract>
    <ns1:habitat>

Scots pine in Stockholm archipelago, Sweden
Scots pine in Stockholm archipelago, Sweden
Scots pine in Stockholm archipelago, Sweden
Pinus sylvestris
is the only pine native to northern Europe,


ranging from
Western Europe
to Eastern
Siberia
, south to the
Caucasus Mountains
and
Anatolia
, and north to well inside the
Arctic Circle
in
Fennoscandia
. In the north of its range, it occurs from sea level to 1,000 m (3,300 ft), while in the south of its range it is a mountain tree, growing at 1,200–2,600 m (3,900–8,500 ft) altitude.




Pinus sylvestris




Western Europe
Siberia
Caucasus Mountains
Anatolia
Arctic Circle
Fennoscandia








The species is mainly found on poorer, sandy soils, rocky outcrops, peat bogs or close to the forest limit. On fertile sites, the pine is out-competed by other tree species, usually
spruce
or
broad-leaved trees
.

spruce
broad-leaved trees

</ns1:habitat>
    <ns1:ecology>

It forms either pure forests or mixes with
Norway spruce
,
common juniper
,
silver birch
,
European rowan
,
Eurasian aspen
and other
hardwood
species. In central and southern Europe, it occurs with numerous additional species, including
European black pine
,
mountain pine
,
Macedonian pine
, and
Swiss pine
. In the eastern part of its range, it occurs with
Siberian pine
, among others.


Norway spruce
common juniper
silver birch
European rowan
Eurasian aspen
hardwood
European black pine
mountain pine
Macedonian pine
Swiss pine
Siberian pine




In 2020, black spot needle blight was found on hundreds of
Pinus sylvestris
var.
mongolica
trees in four forest farms in northeastern China. It first appeared on the upper part of the needles, and then the needles became withered and gradually showed light black spots, although they still remained green. As the fungal disease progressed, the needles eventually died and turned gray with many dark black spots. The fungus was identified as
Heterotruncatella spartii
(within the family
Sporocadaceae
) based on morphology and molecular methods.

Pinus sylvestris
mongolica
Heterotruncatella spartii
Heterotruncatella spartii
Sporocadaceae

</ns1:ecology>
    <ns1:taxonomy>No information found on the section.</ns1:taxonomy>
    <ns1:comments>[]</ns1:comments>
    <ns1:images>[]</ns1:images>
    <ns1:positioning>---</ns1:positioning>
    <ns1:zone>Zona 10 - Sectia Rosarium</ns1:zone>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
