<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:ns1="https://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://127.0.0.1:5000/zone/Zona%203%20-%20Complexul%20de%20Sere/plant/Opuntia">
    <ns1:label>Opuntia</ns1:label>
    <ns1:abstract xml:lang="en">Opuntia, commonly called prickly pear or pear cactus, is a genus of flowering plants in the cactus family Cactaceae. Prickly pears are also known as tuna (fruit), sabra, nopal (paddle, plural nopales) from the Nahuatl word nōpalli for the pads, or nostle, from the Nahuatl word nōchtli for the fruit; or paddle cactus. The genus is named for the Ancient Greek city of Opus, where, according to Theophrastus, an edible plant grew and could be propagated by rooting its leaves. The most common culinary species is the Indian fig opuntia (O. ficus-indica).</ns1:abstract>
    <ns1:subspecies>['Many, [[#Species']</ns1:subspecies>
    <ns1:habitat>

Like most true cactus species, prickly pears are native only to the
Americas
. Through human action, they have since been introduced to many other areas of the world.


Prickly pear species are found in abundance in
Mexico
, especially in the central and western regions, and in the
Caribbean
islands (
West Indies
). In the
United States
, prickly pears are native to many areas of the arid, semi-arid, and drought-prone
Western
and
South Central
United States, including the lower elevations of the
Rocky Mountains
and southern
Great Plains
, where species such as
O. phaeacantha
and
O. polyacantha
have become dominant, and to the desert Southwest, where several types are endemic. Prickly pear cactus is also native to sandy coastal beach scrub environments of the
East Coast
from
Florida
to southern
Connecticut
, where
O. humifusa
,
O. stricta
, and
O. pusilla
, are found from the East Coast south into the
Caribbean
and the
Bahamas
.  Additionally, the eastern prickly pear is native to the midwestern "sand prairies" near major river systems, such as the Mississippi, Illinois, and Ohio rivers.

The plant also occurs naturally in hilly areas of southern
Illinois
, and sandy or rocky areas of northern Illinois.

Americas




Mexico
Caribbean
West Indies
United States
Western
South Central
Rocky Mountains
Great Plains
O. phaeacantha
O. phaeacantha
O. polyacantha
O. polyacantha
East Coast
Florida
Connecticut
O. humifusa
O. humifusa
O. stricta
O. stricta
O. pusilla
O. pusilla
Caribbean
Bahamas


Illinois


Opuntia
species are the most cold-tolerant of the lowland cacti, extending into western and southern
Canada
. One
subspecies
,
O. fragilis
var.
fragilis
, has been found growing along the
Beatton River
in north-eastern
British Columbia
, southwest of
Cecil Lake
at 56° 17’ N latitude and 120° 39’ W longitude.

Others are seen in the Kleskun Hills Natural Area of north-west
Alberta
at 55° 15’ 30’’ N latitude and 118° 30’ 36’’ W longitude.

Opuntia
Canada
subspecies
O. fragilis
var.
fragilis
O. fragilis
fragilis
Beatton River
British Columbia
Cecil Lake


Alberta


Prickly pears produce a fruit known as
tuna
, commonly eaten in
Mexico
and in the
Mediterranean region
, which is also used to make
aguas frescas
.

The fruit can be red, wine-red, green, or yellow-orange. In the
Galápagos Islands
, the Galápagos prickly pear,
O. galapageia
, has previously been treated as a number of different species, but is now only divided into varieties and subvarieties.

Most of these are confined to one or a few islands, so they have been described as "an excellent example of
adaptive radiation
".

On the whole, islands with tall, trunked varieties are also the home of giant tortoises, whereas islands lacking tortoises have low or prostrate forms of
Opuntia
. Prickly pears are a prime source of food for the common giant tortoises in the Galápagos Islands, so they are important in the food web.
tuna
Mexico
Mediterranean region
aguas frescas
aguas frescas


Galápagos Islands
O. galapageia
O. galapageia


adaptive radiation


Opuntia
Charles Darwin
was the first to note that the cacti have
thigmotactic
anthers
. When the anthers are touched, they curl over, depositing their
pollen
. That movement can be seen by gently poking the anthers of an open
Opuntia
flower
. The same trait has
evolved convergently
in other species (e.g.
Lophophora
).
Charles Darwin
thigmotactic
anthers
pollen
Opuntia
flower
evolved convergently
Lophophora
Lophophora
Prickly pears (mostly
O. stricta
) were originally imported into Europe during the 16th century.

They are now found in the Mediterranean region of
Northern Africa
, especially in
Algeria
,
Morocco
and
Tunisia
, where they grow all over the countryside, and in parts of
Southern Europe
, especially
Spain
, where they can be found in the east, south-east, and south of the country, and also in
Malta
, where they grow all over the islands. They can be found in enormous numbers in parts of
South Africa
, where they were introduced from South America. The prickly pear is considered an
invasive species
in
Australia
,
Ethiopia
,
South Africa
, and
Hawaii
, among other locations.

O. stricta


Northern Africa
Algeria
Morocco
Tunisia
Southern Europe
Spain
Malta
South Africa
invasive species
Australia
Ethiopia
South Africa
Hawaii


The first introduction of prickly pears into
Australia
is ascribed to the founding governor of the New South Wales colony,
Arthur Phillip
, and the earliest European colonists, in 1788. Brought from
Brazil
to
Sydney
, they were most likely
O. monacantha
. That variety did not spread beyond the east coast. However, a number of other types of prickly pear were introduced to Australian gardens in the mid-19th century. The cactus was also used as agricultural fencing and a feedstock for animals in times of drought,


as well as in an attempt to establish a
cochineal
dye industry.
Australia
Arthur Phillip
Brazil
Sydney
O. monacantha




cochineal
The cactus quickly became a widespread
invasive weed
in the dry interior climate west of the
Great Dividing Range
, in New South Wales and
Queensland
,

eventually converting 260,000 km
2
(101,000 sq mi) of farming land into an impenetrable green jungle of prickly pear, in places 6 m (20 ft) high. Scores of farmers were driven off their land by what they called the "green hell", and their abandoned homes were crushed under the cactus growth, which advanced at a rate of 400,000 hectares (1,000,000 acres) per year.

invasive weed
Great Dividing Range
Queensland


2


In 1919, the
Australian federal government
established the Commonwealth Prickly Pear Board to coordinate efforts with state governments to eradicate the weed. Early attempts, comprising mechanical removal and poisonous chemicals failed. As a last resort, biological control was attempted.

In 1925, the
Cactoblastis cactorum
moth
was introduced from
South America
, and its larvae rapidly began to control the infestation.
Alan Dodd
, the son of the noted entomologist
Frederick Parkhurst Dodd
, was a leading official in combating the prickly pear menace. A memorial hall in
Boonarga, Queensland
, commemorates the efforts of the moth.

The release of cochineal insects, that eat the cactus and simultaneously kill the plant, has also proven an effective measure for combating its spread.

Australian federal government


Cactoblastis cactorum
Cactoblastis cactorum
moth
South America
Alan Dodd
Frederick Parkhurst Dodd
Boonarga, Queensland




Natural distribution of the plant occurs via consumption and associated
seed dispersal
by many animals, including
antelopes
, nonhuman
primates
,
elephants
, birds, and humans.

When ingested by elephants, the sharp components of the plant cause harm to the mouth, stomach, and intestines.

seed dispersal
antelopes
primates
elephants



</ns1:habitat>
    <ns1:ecology>

See also:
Prickly pears in Australia
and
Prickly pears in South Africa
Prickly pears in Australia
Prickly pears in South Africa
O. ficus-indica
thrives in regions with mild winters having a prolonged dry spell followed by hot summers with occasional rain and relatively low humidity.

A mean annual rainfall of
350–500 mm (14–
19
+
1
⁄
2
in) provides good growth rates.

O. ficus-indica
proliferates in various soils ranging from sub
acid
to sub
alkaline
, with clay content not exceeding 15–20% and the soil well-drained.

The shallow root system enables the plant to grow in shallow, loose soils, such as on mountain slopes.

Opuntia
spreads into large clonal colonies, which contribute to its being considered a
noxious weed
in some places.


O. ficus-indica


19
+
1
⁄
2
+
1
2


O. ficus-indica
acid
alkaline




Opuntia
noxious weed




Animals that eat
Opuntia
include the
prickly pear island snail
and
Cyclura
rock iguanas. The fruit are relished by many arid-land animals, chiefly birds, which thus help distribute the seeds.
Opuntia
pathogens
include the sac fungus
Colletotrichum coccodes
and
Sammons'
Opuntia
virus
. The ant
Crematogaster opuntiae
and the spider
Theridion opuntia
are named because of their association with prickly pear cactus.
Opuntia
prickly pear island snail
Cyclura
Cyclura
Opuntia
pathogens
Colletotrichum coccodes
Colletotrichum coccodes
Sammons'
Opuntia
virus
Opuntia
Crematogaster opuntiae
Crematogaster opuntiae
Theridion opuntia
Theridion opuntia</ns1:ecology>
    <ns1:taxonomy>

O. lindheimeri
,
Behbahan
O. lindheimeri
,
Behbahan
O. lindheimeri
O. lindheimeri
Behbahan
O. cochenillifera
O. cochenillifera
O. cochenillifera
O. cochenillifera
When
Carl Linnaeus
published
Species Plantarum
in 1753 – the starting point for modern botanical nomenclature – he placed all the species of cactus known to him in one genus,
Cactus
. In 1754, the Scottish botanist
Philip Miller
divided them into several genera, including
Opuntia
. He distinguished the genus largely on the form of its flowers and fruits.

Carl Linnaeus
Species Plantarum
Species Plantarum
Cactus
Philip Miller
Opuntia


Considerable variation of taxonomy occurs within
Opuntia
species, resulting in names being created for variants or subtypes within a species, and use of
DNA sequencing
to define and isolate various species.

Opuntia
DNA sequencing

</ns1:taxonomy>
    <ns1:comments>[]</ns1:comments>
    <ns1:images>[]</ns1:images>
    <ns1:positioning>---</ns1:positioning>
    <ns1:zone>Zona 3 - Complexul de Sere</ns1:zone>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
