<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:ns1="http://www.geneontology.org/formats/oboInOwl#"
   xmlns:ns2="https://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:ns3="https://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:ns4="http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/ncbitaxon#"
   xmlns:ns5="https://www.w3.org/2002/07/"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://127.0.0.1:5000/zone/Zona%201%20-%20Sectia%20Sistematica/plant/Apiaceae">
    <rdfs:label>Apiaceae</rdfs:label>
    <ns2:abstract xml:lang="en">Apiaceae or Umbelliferae is a family of mostly aromatic flowering plants named after the type genus Apium and commonly known as the celery, carrot or parsley family, or simply as umbellifers. It is the 16th-largest family of flowering plants, with more than 3,700 species in 434 genera including such well-known and economically important plants as ajwain, angelica, anise, asafoetida, caraway, carrot, celery, chervil, coriander, cumin, dill, fennel, lovage, cow parsley, parsley, parsnip and sea holly, as well as silphium, a plant whose identity is unclear and which may be extinct. The family Apiaceae includes a significant number of phototoxic species, such as giant hogweed, and a smaller number of highly poisonous species, such as poison hemlock, water hemlock, spotted cowbane, fool's parsley, and various species of water dropwort.</ns2:abstract>
    <ns3:subspecies>['Mackinlayoideae (Plunkett &amp; Lowry)', 'Azorelloideae (Plunkett &amp; Lowry)', 'Saniculoideae (Burnett)', 'Apioideae (Seem.)']</ns3:subspecies>
    <ns3:ecology>

The black swallowtail butterfly,
Papilio polyxenes
, uses the family Apiaceae for food and host plants for
oviposition
.

The
22-spot ladybird
is also commonly found eating mildew on these plants.

Papilio polyxenes
Papilio polyxenes
oviposition


22-spot ladybird

</ns3:ecology>
    <ns3:taxonomy>

Apiaceae was first described by
John Lindley
in 1836.

The name is derived from the type genus
Apium
, which was originally used by
Pliny the Elder
circa 50 AD for a
celery
-like plant.

The alternative name for the family, Umbelliferae, derives from the
inflorescence
being generally in the form of a compound
umbel
. The family was one of the first to be recognized as a distinct group in Jacques Daleschamps' 1586
Historia generalis plantarum
. With
Robert Morison's
1672
Plantarum umbelliferarum distribution nova
it became the first group of plants for which a systematic study was published.
John Lindley


Apium
Apium
Pliny the Elder
celery


inflorescence
umbel
Historia generalis plantarum
Robert Morison's
Plantarum umbelliferarum distribution nova
The family is solidly placed within the
Apiales
order in the
APG III system
. It is closely related to
Araliaceae
and the boundaries between these families remain unclear. Traditionally groups within the family have been delimited largely based on fruit
morphology
, and the results from this have not been congruent with the more recent molecular
phylogenetic
analyses. The subfamilial and tribal classification for the family is currently in a state of flux, with many of the groups being found to be grossly
paraphyletic
or
polyphyletic
.

Apiales
APG III system
Araliaceae
morphology
phylogenetic
paraphyletic
polyphyletic

</ns3:taxonomy>
    <rdf:zone>http://127.0.0.1:5000/zone/Zona%201%20-%20Sectia%20Sistematica</rdf:zone>
    <rdf:type>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#Class</rdf:type>
    <rdfs:subClassOf>http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/NCBITaxon_364270</rdfs:subClassOf>
    <ns1:hasExactSynonym>carrot family</ns1:hasExactSynonym>
    <ns4:has_rank>http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/NCBITaxon_family</ns4:has_rank>
    <ns5:owlsameAs>['http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/NCBITaxon_4037', 'https://dbpedia.org/page/Apiaceae']</ns5:owlsameAs>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
