<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:ns1="http://www.geneontology.org/formats/oboInOwl#"
   xmlns:ns2="https://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:ns3="https://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:ns4="http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/ncbitaxon#"
   xmlns:ns5="https://www.w3.org/2002/07/"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://127.0.0.1:5000/zone/Zona%201%20-%20Sectia%20Sistematica/plant/Poaceae">
    <rdfs:label>Poaceae</rdfs:label>
    <ns2:abstract xml:lang="en">Poaceae (/poʊˈeɪsiaɪ/) or Gramineae (/ɡrəˈmɪniaɪ/) is a large and nearly ubiquitous family of monocotyledonous flowering plants commonly known as grasses. It includes the cereal grasses, bamboos and the grasses of natural grassland and species cultivated in lawns and pasture. The latter are commonly referred to collectively as grass. With around 780 genera and around 12,000 species, the Poaceae is the fifth-largest plant family, following the Asteraceae, Orchidaceae, Fabaceae and Rubiaceae. The Poaceae are the most economically important plant family, providing staple foods from domesticated cereal crops such as maize, wheat, rice, barley, and millet as well as feed for meat-producing animals. They provide, through direct human consumption, just over one-half (51%) of all dietary energy; rice provides 20%, wheat supplies 20%, maize (corn) 5.5%, and other grains 6%. Some members of the Poaceae are used as building materials (bamboo, thatch, and straw); others can provide a source of biofuel, primarily via the conversion of maize to ethanol. Grasses have stems that are hollow except at the nodes and narrow alternate leaves borne in two ranks. The lower part of each leaf encloses the stem, forming a leaf-sheath. The leaf grows from the base of the blade, an adaptation allowing it to cope with frequent grazing. Grasslands such as savannah and prairie where grasses are dominant are estimated to constitute 40.5% of the land area of the Earth, excluding Greenland and Antarctica. Grasses are also an important part of the vegetation in many other habitats, including wetlands, forests and tundra. Though they are commonly called "grasses", groups such as the seagrasses, rushes and sedges fall outside this family. The rushes and sedges are related to the Poaceae, being members of the order Poales, but the seagrasses are members of order Alismatales. However, all of them belong to the monocot group of plants.</ns2:abstract>
    <ns3:subspecies>[' Anomochlooideae', ' Aristidoideae', ' Arundinoideae', ' Bambusoideae', ' Chloridoideae', ' Danthonioideae', ' Ehrhartoideae', ' Micrairoideae', ' Panicoideae', ' Pharoideae', ' Pooideae', ' Puelioideae']</ns3:subspecies>
    <ns3:ecology>Wind-blown grass in the
Valles Caldera
in New Mexico, United States
Wind-blown grass in the
Valles Caldera
in New Mexico, United States
Valles Caldera
Grasses are the
dominant
vegetation in many habitats, including
grassland
,
salt-marsh
,
reedswamp
and
steppes
. They also occur as a smaller part of the vegetation in almost every other terrestrial habitat.

Grass-dominated
biomes
are called grasslands. If only large, contiguous areas of grasslands are counted, these biomes cover 31% of the planet's land.

Grasslands include
pampas
,
steppes
, and
prairies
.

Grasses provide food to many
grazing
mammals,

as well as to many species of
butterflies
and
moths
.


Many types of animals eat grass as their main source of food, and are called
graminivores
– these include
cattle
,
sheep
,
horses
,
rabbits
and many
invertebrates
, such as
grasshoppers
and the caterpillars of many
brown butterflies
. Grasses are also eaten by
omnivorous
or even occasionally by primarily
carnivorous
animals.
dominant
grassland
salt-marsh
reedswamp
steppes

citation needed
citation needed
citation needed
biomes


pampas
steppes
prairies


grazing


butterflies
moths




graminivores
graminivores
cattle
sheep
horses
rabbits
invertebrates
grasshoppers
brown butterflies
omnivorous
carnivorous
A
kangaroo
eating grass
A
kangaroo
eating grass
kangaroo
Grasses dominate certain
biomes
, especially
temperate grasslands
, because many species are adapted to grazing and fire.

biomes
temperate grasslands


Grasses are unusual in that the
meristem
is near the bottom of the plant; hence, grasses can quickly recover from cropping at the top.

The evolution of large grazing animals in the
Cenozoic
contributed to the spread of grasses. Without large grazers, fire-cleared areas are quickly colonized by grasses, and with enough rain, tree seedlings. Trees eventually outcompete most grasses. Trampling grazers kill seedling trees but not grasses.

: 137
meristem


Cenozoic


: 137
: 137</ns3:ecology>
    <ns3:taxonomy>The name Poaceae was given by
John Hendley Barnhart
in 1895,

: 7
based on the tribe Poeae described in 1814 by
Robert Brown
, and the type genus
Poa
described in 1753 by
Carl Linnaeus
. The term is derived from the Ancient Greek
πόα (póa, "fodder")
.
John Hendley Barnhart


: 7
: 7
Robert Brown
Poa
Poa
Carl Linnaeus
πόα (póa, "fodder")</ns3:taxonomy>
    <rdf:zone>http://127.0.0.1:5000/zone/Zona%201%20-%20Sectia%20Sistematica</rdf:zone>
    <rdf:type>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#Class</rdf:type>
    <rdfs:subClassOf>http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/NCBITaxon_38820</rdfs:subClassOf>
    <ns1:hasExactSynonym>grass family</ns1:hasExactSynonym>
    <ns4:has_rank>http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/NCBITaxon_family</ns4:has_rank>
    <ns5:owlsameAs>['http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/NCBITaxon_4479', 'https://dbpedia.org/page/Poaceae']</ns5:owlsameAs>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
