<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:ns1="https://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:ns2="https://www.w3.org/2002/07/"
   xmlns:ns3="http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/ncbitaxon#"
   xmlns:ns4="https://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://127.0.0.1:5000/zone/Zona%204%20-%20Sectia%20Flora%20si%20Vegetatia%20Romaniei/plant/Quercus%20frainetto">
    <rdfs:label>Quercus frainetto</rdfs:label>
    <ns4:abstract xml:lang="en">Quercus frainetto (syn. Quercus conferta Kit., Quercus farnetto Ten.), commonly known as the Hungarian oak or Italian oak, is a species of oak, native to southeastern Europe (parts of Italy, the Balkans, parts of Hungary, Romania) and Turkey; it is classified in Quercus sect. Mesobalanus.</ns4:abstract>
    <ns1:habitat>

See also:
Balkan mixed forests
Balkan mixed forests
Hungarian oak forest
Hungarian oak forest
The centre of the tree's native range is in the
Balkans
. It is adapted to the subcontinental climate of southeastern Europe, but the main factor of its occurrence at a particular site is the soil. It is specially adapted to heavy acidic soils (
cambisols
and
vertisols
), typical of Kosovo, Serbia, Bulgaria and Romania. These soils are usually leached out, very dry in the summer and sometimes waterlogged in the spring. However, the Hungarian oak does not tolerate flooding or high water tables. It is also extremely sensitive to the presence of lime in the soil. Hence, in contradiction to its English vernacular name, which was assigned when the
Kingdom of Hungary
controlled large parts of the Balkans, the Hungarian oak is a very rare tree in modern Hungary, where the soils are generally very rich in lime. The Hungarian oak-
Turkey oak
forest (
Quercetum frainetto-cerris
Rud.) is the most widespread association of this oak in the Balkans, which is also the most common forest type in Serbia and Kosovo.
Balkans
cambisols
vertisols
Kingdom of Hungary
Turkey oak
Quercetum frainetto-cerris
Quercetum frainetto-cerris</ns1:habitat>
    <rdf:zone>http://127.0.0.1:5000/zone/Zona%204%20-%20Sectia%20Flora%20si%20Vegetatia%20Romaniei</rdf:zone>
    <rdf:type>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#Class</rdf:type>
    <rdfs:subClassOf>http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/NCBITaxon_3511</rdfs:subClassOf>
    <ns3:has_rank>http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/NCBITaxon_species</ns3:has_rank>
    <ns2:owlsameAs>['http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/NCBITaxon_225354', 'https://dbpedia.org/page/Quercus frainetto']</ns2:owlsameAs>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
