<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:ns1="http://www.geneontology.org/formats/oboInOwl#"
   xmlns:ns2="https://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:ns3="https://www.w3.org/2002/07/"
   xmlns:ns4="http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/ncbitaxon#"
   xmlns:ns5="https://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://127.0.0.1:5000/zone/Zona%203%20-%20Complexul%20de%20Sere/plant/Coffea%20arabica">
    <rdfs:label>Coffea arabica</rdfs:label>
    <ns5:abstract xml:lang="en">Coffea arabica (/əˈræbɪkə/), also known as the Arabic coffee, is a species of flowering plant in the coffee and madder family Rubiaceae. It is believed to be the first species of coffee to have been cultivated and is currently the dominant cultivar, representing about 60% of global production. Coffee produced from the less acidic, more bitter, and more highly caffeinated robusta bean (C. canephora) makes up most of the remaining coffee production. Arabica coffee originates from and was first cultivated in Yemen, and documented by the 12th century. Coffea arabica is called ‏بُنّ‎ (būnn) in Arabic, borrowed from the Amharic "Buna".</ns5:abstract>
    <ns2:habitat>

Endemic to the southwestern
highlands
of
Ethiopia
,

Coffea arabica
is today grown in dozens of countries between the
Tropic of Capricorn
and the
Tropic of Cancer
.

It is commonly used as an
understory
shrub. It has also been recovered from the
Boma Plateau
in
South Sudan
.
Coffea arabica
is also found on Mount
Marsabit
in northern
Kenya
, but it is unclear whether this is a truly native or naturalised occurrence; recent studies support it being naturalised.


The species is widely naturalised in areas outside its native land, in many parts of
Africa
,
Latin America
,
Southeast Asia
,
India
,
China
, and assorted islands in the
Caribbean
and in the
Pacific
.

highlands
Ethiopia


Coffea arabica
Tropic of Capricorn
Tropic of Cancer


understory
Boma Plateau
South Sudan
Coffea arabica
Marsabit
Kenya




Africa
Latin America
Southeast Asia
India
China
Caribbean
Pacific


The coffee tree was first brought to
Hawaii
in 1813, and it began to be extensively grown by about 1850.

It was formerly more widely grown than at present, especially in
Kona
,

and it persists after cultivation in many areas. In some valleys, it is a highly invasive weed.

In the
Udawattakele
and Gannoruwa Forest Reserves near Kandy, Sri Lanka, coffee shrubs are also a problematic invasive species.

Hawaii


Kona




Udawattakele


Coffee has been produced in Queensland and New South Wales of Australia, starting in the 1980s and 90s.

The Wet Tropics Management Authority has classified
Coffea arabica
as an environmental weed for southeast Queensland due to its invasiveness in non-agricultural areas.




Coffea arabica



</ns2:habitat>
    <ns2:taxonomy>

Coffea arabica
was first
described
scientifically by
Antoine de Jussieu
, who named it
Jasminum arabicum
after studying a specimen from the
Botanic Gardens of Amsterdam
.
Linnaeus
placed it in its own genus
Coffea
in 1737.

Coffea arabica
described
Antoine de Jussieu
Jasminum arabicum
Botanic Gardens of Amsterdam
Linnaeus
Coffea
Coffea


Coffea arabica
is one of the
polyploid
species of the genus
Coffea
,
as it carries 4 copies of the 11 chromosomes (44 total) instead of the 2 copies of diploid species. Specifically,
Coffea arabica
is itself the result of a hybridization between the diploids
Coffea canephora
and
Coffea eugenioides,

thus making it an
allotetraploid
, with
two
copies of two different genomes. This hybridization event at the origin of
Coffea arabica
is estimated between 1.08 million and 543,000 years ago and is linked to changing environmental conditions in East Africa.

Coffea arabica
polyploid
Coffea
,
Coffea
Coffea arabica
Coffea canephora
Coffea canephora
Coffea eugenioides,


allotetraploid
two
Coffea arabica

</ns2:taxonomy>
    <rdf:zone>http://127.0.0.1:5000/zone/Zona%203%20-%20Complexul%20de%20Sere</rdf:zone>
    <rdf:type>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#Class</rdf:type>
    <rdfs:subClassOf>http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/NCBITaxon_33090</rdfs:subClassOf>
    <ns1:hasExactSynonym>coffee</ns1:hasExactSynonym>
    <ns4:has_rank>http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/NCBITaxon_species</ns4:has_rank>
    <ns3:owlsameAs>['http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/NCBITaxon_13443', 'https://dbpedia.org/page/Coffea arabica']</ns3:owlsameAs>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
