<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:ns1="https://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:ns2="http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/ncbitaxon#"
   xmlns:ns3="https://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:ns4="https://www.w3.org/2002/07/"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://127.0.0.1:5000/zone/Zona%203%20-%20Complexul%20de%20Sere/plant/Dieffenbachia">
    <rdfs:label>Dieffenbachia</rdfs:label>
    <ns1:abstract xml:lang="en">Dieffenbachia /ˌdiːfɪnˈbækiə/, commonly known as dumb cane or leopard lily, is a genus of tropical flowering plants in the family Araceae. It is native to the New World Tropics from Mexico and the West Indies south to Argentina. Some species are widely cultivated as ornamental plants, especially as houseplants, and have become naturalized on a few tropical islands. Dieffenbachia is a perennial herbaceous plant with straight stem, simple and alternate leaves containing white spots and flecks, making it attractive as indoor foliage. Species in this genus are popular as houseplants because of their tolerance of shade. The English names, dumb cane and mother-in-law's tongue (also used for Sansevieria species) refer to the poisoning effect of raphides, which can cause temporary inability to speak. Dieffenbachia was named by Heinrich Wilhelm Schott, director of the Botanical Gardens in Vienna, to honor his head gardener Joseph Dieffenbach (1796–1863).</ns1:abstract>
    <ns3:ecology>

In a survey that began in 1998, researchers in
Costa Rica
noticed that the strawberry poison frog
Oophaga pumilio
, deposited almost all (89%) of their tadpoles on the leaf axils of
Dieffenbachia
. As a result, the frog population fluctuated with the abundance of
Dieffenbachia
, especially in secondary forests
. A majority of the plants were eradicated by 2012 when the surveyors returned to the same area, with only 28% of 2002 plant numbers remaining. Researchers concluded that the reason for the rapid decline in
Dieffenbachia
was due to increased abundance of the collared peccary
Dicotyles tajacu
in the
La Selva Biological Station
research area; a small pig-like animal that feeds on
Dieffenbachia
and other plants.

Costa Rica
Oophaga pumilio
Oophaga pumilio
Dieffenbachia
Dieffenbachia
Dieffenbachia
Dicotyles tajacu
Dicotyles tajacu
La Selva Biological Station
Dieffenbachia

</ns3:ecology>
    <rdf:zone>http://127.0.0.1:5000/zone/Zona%203%20-%20Complexul%20de%20Sere</rdf:zone>
    <rdf:type>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#Class</rdf:type>
    <rdfs:subClassOf>http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/NCBITaxon_293488</rdfs:subClassOf>
    <ns2:has_rank>http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/NCBITaxon_genus</ns2:has_rank>
    <ns4:owlsameAs>['http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/NCBITaxon_42195', 'https://dbpedia.org/page/Dieffenbachia']</ns4:owlsameAs>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
