<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:ns1="https://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://127.0.0.1:5000/zone/Zona%208%20-%20Sectia%20Dendrarium/plant/Sorbus%20aucuparia">
    <ns1:label>Sorbus aucuparia</ns1:label>
    <ns1:abstract xml:lang="en">Sorbus aucuparia, commonly called rowan (UK: /ˈrəʊən/, US: /ˈroʊən/) and mountain-ash, is a species of deciduous tree or shrub in the rose family. It is a highly variable species, and botanists have used different definitions of the species to include or exclude trees native to certain areas; a recent definition includes trees native to most of Europe and parts of Asia, as well as northern Africa. The range extends from Madeira, the British Isles and Iceland to Russia and northern China. Unlike many plants with similar distributions, it is not native to Japan. The tree has a slender trunk with smooth bark, a loose and roundish crown, and its leaves are pinnate in pairs of leaflets on a central vein with a terminal leaflet. It blossoms from May to June in dense corymbs of small yellowish white flowers and develops small red pomes as fruit that ripen from August to October and are eaten by many bird species. The plant is undemanding and frost hardy and colonizes disrupted and inaccessible places as a short-lived pioneer species. The fruit and foliage have been used in the creation of dishes and beverages, as a folk medicine, and as fodder for livestock. Its tough and flexible wood has traditionally been used for woodworking. It is planted to fortify soil in mountain regions or as an ornamental tree and has several cultivars.</ns1:abstract>
    <ns1:habitat>

Growing with
Mountain Pine
in the Italian Alps
Growing with
Mountain Pine
in the Italian Alps
Mountain Pine
Sorbus aucuparia
is found in five subspecies:


Sorbus aucuparia




Sorbus aucuparia
subsp.
aucuparia
: found in most of the species' range, less in the South
Sorbus aucuparia
subsp.
fenenkiana
(Georgiev &amp;
Stoj.
): has thin, sparsely hairy leaflets and depressed-globose fruit, restricted to Bulgaria
Sorbus aucuparia
subsp.
glabrata
(
Wimm.
&amp; Grab.): less hairy, found in Northern Europe and Central European mountains
Sorbus aucuparia
subsp.
praemorsa
(
Guss.
): has hairy leaflets and ovoid fruit, found in Southern Italy, Sicily, and Corsica
Sorbus aucuparia
subsp.
sibirica
(Hedl.): nearly hairless, found in North Eastern Russia
Sorbus aucuparia
subsp.
aucuparia
: found in most of the species' range, less in the South
Sorbus aucuparia
aucuparia
Sorbus aucuparia
subsp.
fenenkiana
(Georgiev &amp;
Stoj.
): has thin, sparsely hairy leaflets and depressed-globose fruit, restricted to Bulgaria
Sorbus aucuparia
fenenkiana
Stoj.
Sorbus aucuparia
subsp.
glabrata
(
Wimm.
&amp; Grab.): less hairy, found in Northern Europe and Central European mountains
Sorbus aucuparia
glabrata
Wimm.
Sorbus aucuparia
subsp.
praemorsa
(
Guss.
): has hairy leaflets and ovoid fruit, found in Southern Italy, Sicily, and Corsica
Sorbus aucuparia
praemorsa
Guss.
Sorbus aucuparia
subsp.
sibirica
(Hedl.): nearly hairless, found in North Eastern Russia
Sorbus aucuparia
sibirica
It can be found in almost all of Europe and the
Caucasus
up to Northern Russia and
Siberia
, but it is not native to Southern Spain, Southern Greece, Sardinia

, the
Balearic Islands
, the
Azores
, and the
Faroe Islands
.


The species was introduced as an ornamental species in
North America
.

It is widespread from plains to mountains up to the
tree line
where it grows as the only deciduous tree species among
krummholz
.

In the Alps it grows at elevations of up to 2,000 m (6,600 ft).

S. aucuparia
appears north of the
boreal forest
at the arctic tree line; in Norway, it is found up to the
71st parallel north
.


It has naturalized in America from Washington to Alaska and eastward in Canada and the northeast of the US very successfully.
Caucasus
Siberia

dubious
–
discuss
dubious
dubious
–
discuss
discuss
Balearic Islands
Azores
Faroe Islands




North America


tree line
krummholz




S. aucuparia
boreal forest
71st parallel north




S. aucuparia
is an undemanding species and can withstand shade.

It is frost hardy and can tolerate winter dryness and a brief
growing season
.

The plant is also resistant to air pollution, wind, and snow pressure.


It mostly grows on soil that is moderately dry to moderately damp, acidic, low on nutrients, sandy, and loose.

It often grows in stony soil or clay soil, but also sandy soil or wet peat.

The plant grows best on fresh, loose, and fertile soil, prefers average humidity, and does not tolerate saline soil or waterlogging.



It can be found in light woodland of all kinds and as a
pioneer species
over fallen dead trees or in clearcuttings, and at the edge of forests or at the sides of roads.

The seeds germinate easily, so the plant may appear on inaccessible rock, ruins, branch forks, or on hollow trees.

S. aucuparia


growing season
















pioneer species




The tallest
S. aucuparia
in the United Kingdom stands in the
Chiltern Hills
in
South East England
. This exceptional specimen is 28 m (92 ft) tall and has a trunk diameter of 56 cm (22 in).

In Germany, an unusually large specimen is located near
Wendisch Waren
, a village in
Mecklenburg-Vorpommern
. This tree stands at more than 15 m (49 ft) tall, is around 100 years old, and has a diameter of 70 cm (28 in).

The tallest known specimen in Ireland is an 18 m (59 ft) tall specimen at
Glenstal Abbey
,
County Limerick
.

S. aucuparia
Chiltern Hills
South East England


Wendisch Waren
Mecklenburg-Vorpommern


Glenstal Abbey
County Limerick

</ns1:habitat>
    <ns1:ecology>

Damage caused by game animal
Damage caused by game animal
The species is pollinated by bees and flies.

Its seeds are not digested by birds and are thus propagated by being passed intact in their droppings.

The fruit are eaten by about 60 bird species and several mammals.

They are liked particularly by
thrushes
and other songbirds, and are also eaten by
cloven-hoofed game
,
red fox
,
European badger
,
dormouse
, and
squirrel
.


The fruit are eaten by migratory birds in winter, including
Bohemian waxwing
,
spotted nutcracker
, and
redwing
.

Cloven-hoofed game also excessively browse foliage and bark.

The plant roots can be found in symbiosis with
arbuscular mycorrhizal
and less commonly with
ectomycorrhizal
fungi.








thrushes
cloven-hoofed game
red fox
European badger
dormouse
squirrel




Bohemian waxwing
spotted nutcracker
redwing




arbuscular mycorrhizal
ectomycorrhizal




It is usually later superseded by larger forest trees.

In Central Europe it often grows in association with
red elderberry
,
goat willow
,
Eurasian aspen
, and
silver birch
.

The plant is highly flammable and tends not to accumulate
plant litter
.




red elderberry
goat willow
Eurasian aspen
silver birch


plant litter




Other species of the genus
Sorbus
easily hybridize with
S. aucuparia
and
hybrid speciation
can result; hybrids include
Sorbus × hybrida
, a small tree with oval serrated leaves and 2 to 3 pairs of leaflets, which is a hybrid with
Sorbus × intermedia
, and
S. thuringiaca
, a medium-size tree with elongated leaves and 1 to 3 pairs of leaflets that are sometimes fused at the central vein, which is a hybrid with
S. aria
.

Sorbus
S. aucuparia
hybrid speciation
Sorbus × hybrida
Sorbus × hybrida
Sorbus × intermedia
Sorbus × intermedia
S. thuringiaca
S. aria
S. aria


The main pests for
S. aucuparia
are the apple fruit moth
Argyresthia conjugella
and the mountain-ash sawfly
Hoplocampa alpina
.


The rust fungus
Gymnosporangium cornutum
produces leaf galls.

The leaves are not palatable to insects, but are used by insect larvae, including by the moth
Venusia cambrica
, the case-bearer moth
Coleophora anatipennella
, and
leaf miners
of the genus
Stigmella
. The snail
Cornu aspersum
feeds on the leaves.

The plant can suffer from
fire blight
.

S. aucuparia
Argyresthia conjugella
Argyresthia conjugella
Hoplocampa alpina
Hoplocampa alpina




Gymnosporangium cornutum
Gymnosporangium cornutum


Venusia cambrica
Venusia cambrica
Coleophora anatipennella
Coleophora anatipennella
leaf miners
Stigmella
Stigmella
Cornu aspersum
Cornu aspersum


fire blight

</ns1:ecology>
    <ns1:taxonomy>
</ns1:taxonomy>
    <ns1:positioning>---</ns1:positioning>
    <ns1:zone>Zona 8 - Sectia Dendrarium</ns1:zone>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
