<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:ns1="http://www.geneontology.org/formats/oboInOwl#"
   xmlns:ns2="https://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:ns3="https://www.w3.org/2002/07/"
   xmlns:ns4="http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/ncbitaxon#"
   xmlns:ns5="https://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://127.0.0.1:5000/zone/Zona%207%20-%20Sectia%20Plante%20Utile/plant/Picea%20abies">
    <rdfs:label>Picea abies</rdfs:label>
    <ns5:abstract xml:lang="en">Picea abies, the Norway spruce or European spruce, is a species of spruce native to Northern, Central and Eastern Europe. It has branchlets that typically hang downwards, and the largest cones of any spruce, 9–17 cm long. It is very closely related to the Siberian spruce (Picea obovata), which replaces it east of the Ural Mountains, and with which it hybridizes freely. The Norway spruce has a wide distribution for it being planted for its wood, and is the species used as the main Christmas tree in several countries around the world. It was the first gymnosperm to have its genome sequenced. The Latin specific epithet abies means “like Abies, Fir tree”</ns5:abstract>
    <ns2:taxonomy>

Cones of
P. obovata
and
Picea abies
Cones of
P. obovata
are short and have rounded scales.
Cones of
P. abies
are longer and have pointed scales.
Cones of
P. obovata
and
Picea abies
Cones of
P. obovata
are short and have rounded scales.
Cones of
P. abies
are longer and have pointed scales.
Cones of
P. obovata
and
Picea abies
Cones of
P. obovata
and
Picea abies
P. obovata
Picea abies
Cones of
P. obovata
are short and have rounded scales.
Cones of
P. abies
are longer and have pointed scales.
Cones of
P. obovata
are short and have rounded scales.
Cones of
P. obovata
are short and have rounded scales.
P. obovata
Cones of
P. abies
are longer and have pointed scales.
Cones of
P. abies
are longer and have pointed scales.
P. abies
Populations in southeast Europe tend to have on average longer cones with more pointed scales; these are sometimes distinguished as
Picea abies
var.
acuminata
, but there is extensive overlap in variation with trees from other parts of the range.



Picea abies
acuminata






Some botanists treat
Siberian spruce
as a subspecies of Norway spruce, though in their typical forms, they are very distinct, the Siberian spruce having cones only 5–10 cm long, with smoothly rounded scales, and pubescent shoots.



Genetically
Norway and Siberian spruces have turned out to be extremely similar and may be considered as two closely related
subspecies
of
P. abies
.

Siberian spruce






Genetically
subspecies
P. abies


Another spruce with smoothly rounded cone scales and hairy shoots occurs rarely in the Central Alps in eastern
Switzerland
. It is also distinct in having thicker, blue-green leaves. Many texts treat this as a variant of Norway spruce, but it is as distinct as many other spruces, and appears to be more closely related to Siberian spruce (
Picea obovata
), Schrenk's spruce (
Picea schrenkiana
) from central
Asia
and Morinda spruce (
Picea smithiana
) in the
Himalaya
. Treated as a distinct species, it takes the name Alpine spruce (
Picea alpestris
). As with Siberian spruce, it hybridizes extensively with Norway spruce; pure specimens are rare. Hybrids are commonly known as Norwegian spruce, which should not be confused with the pure species Norway spruce.



Switzerland
Picea obovata
Picea obovata
Picea schrenkiana
Picea schrenkiana
Asia
Picea smithiana
Picea smithiana
Himalaya
Picea alpestris
Picea alpestris





</ns2:taxonomy>
    <rdf:zone>http://127.0.0.1:5000/zone/Zona%207%20-%20Sectia%20Plante%20Utile</rdf:zone>
    <rdf:type>http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#Class</rdf:type>
    <rdfs:subClassOf>http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/NCBITaxon_3328</rdfs:subClassOf>
    <ns1:hasExactSynonym>Norway spruce</ns1:hasExactSynonym>
    <ns4:has_rank>http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/NCBITaxon_species</ns4:has_rank>
    <ns3:owlsameAs>['http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/NCBITaxon_3329', 'https://dbpedia.org/page/Picea abies']</ns3:owlsameAs>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
